Curriculum Vitae

Daniel Joseph Gomez

5250 Case Dr, Suite 332 Pleasanton, CA 94566 209.407.8614 – danielgomez@ufl.edu

Objective

My career interests are in the applications cellular biology of fending off emerging pathogens, solving diseases with molecular and biotechnical techniques. I will gain the ins and outs of the Omics through research and academia. I can present data (talk/poster) as it is a big part of the research process. Having worked alongside MDs, PhDs and other fellows, this gave me the insight to the work ethic necessary for a career in medicinal science. Technical writing has always pleased me because I was able to tell and read intricate biological stories. I would like to describe molecular mechanisms, create molecular inventions, and include the structures and functions of elegant peptides and functional ribozymes that point to immunodetections (infections, diseases, disorders, etc.), biomarkers, and extract the pathological implications. After obtaining my BS degree, I'll set myself up to become a doctoral student.

Education

Bachelor of Science. University of Florida. Gainesville, FL

2018-21

Department of Microbiology and Cell Science, IFAS-CALS

MCB - Medical Microbiology and Bacteriology - MCS

Relevant Graduate Coursework

- Intro to the Neurosciences
- Translational Research in NeuroAIDS and Mental Health (TR-NAMH)

John A. Burns School of Medicine, Johns Hopkins University

Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology

NIP - Neuroimmune pharmacology - BSB

2012 - 13

Professional Experience

Student Assistant. Las Positas College. Livermore, CA.

Career & Transfer Center. Disability Center.

Jan 2020 - Present

Research Technician. John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI. Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology

Aug 2012-Dec 2013

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- FACS, Mouse handling, qPCR, NanoDrop
- Autoclave, Vortex, Centrifuge, cell-culture

Scientific Ambassador. UF. Gainesville, FL

Dec 2018 - Feb 2020

- Raise awareness of Agricultural and Life Science
- Immunology, Biology, Microbiology
- Molecular Biology
- Astrobiology

Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- Developing deliverables for market.
- PI- Dr. Miller (~40hrs/week).
- Did not go-through with IRB protocols, products did not make it to human trials

Research Associate. JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI

Jan 2012 - June 2013

- Developing an immunohistochemistry (IHC) system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- PI- Dr. Nerurkar (~40hrs/week).

Biology Assistant. JABSOM Department of Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology. Honolulu, HI

2012-13

- Develop blood-brain barrier for permeability assays
- Flow Cytometry (FACS)
- qPCR

Research Experience

DiVERGE. Scripps Research. Jupiter, FL

Jan 2020

- Science identity and the culture of science
- Crafting applications, Research Writing, Constructing a compelling self-introduction
- Internships and Ongoing research
- The history and background of Scripps Research

Research and Development Coordinator. dosist. San Francisco, CA

Dec 2015-Feb 2016

- Developing disposable bioengineered micro dosed vape pens as deliverables for market.
- Research Human trials (~40hrs/week).
- Dosist pens (relief, bliss, clam, sleep, passion, arousal)

Research Assistant. UCSD School of Medicine Division of Neuroanesthesia. La Jolla, CA

Jan 2014-Jun 2014

- Developing a drug delivery system for Neurocardiological Disease protection.
- Caveolin scaffolding life support for heart organ
- PI- Dr. Patel (~5-15hrs/week).

Research Associate. JABSOM Tropical Medicine, Medical Microbiology, and Pharmacology.

Honolulu, HI Jan 2014-Jun 2014

- Developing an immunohistochemistry system for JCPyV and HIV-1 Disease.
- Immunocytochemistry procedures in kidney and brain
- PI- Dr. Nerurkar (~40hrs/week).

Research Associate. John A. Burns School of Medicine (JABSOM), Honolulu, HI.

Aug 2012-July 2013

- Developing a drug delivery system for HIV-1 Disease in the BBB.
- PI- Dr. Shiramizu (40hrs/week).

Research Interests

Epidemiology	Nanotechnology	Oncology	
Bioinformatics	Translational Research	Neuroscience	
Drug metabolism	Computational Biology	Emerging Pathogens	
Lab skills			
Cell culture (in vivo, in vitro)	Nanoparticle synthesis	PCR/qPCR	
Mouse handling (anosthesia ex	Flow cytometry (in vitro)	P programming	

Cell culture (*in vivo*, *in vitro*)

Nanoparticle synthesis

PCR/qPCR

Mouse handling (anesthesia, *ex*Flow cytometry (*in vitro*)

R programming *vivo*)

BioinformaticsMicroscopySequencingGel ElectrophoresisPython programmingWestern blotsDrug encapsulationDNA/RNA extractionToxicity assays

Excellent computer and analytical skills using a large variety of programs and software, excellent public presentation skills

Publications

Anticipated 2021

Awards and Honors

Undergraduate Research Opportunities Program (UROP) Award

2013

• \$5000 award.

Teaching Experience

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant. 20hrs/week 2011

- CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Talisman)
- CHEM161L General Chemistry Lab I (Dr. Talisman)

University Tutor. 15hrs/week

2011

• CHEM161 General Chemistry (Dr. Hemscheidt)

Tutor. 10hrs/week

2012

Organic Chemistry Tutor

Medical and Clinical Experience

Volunteer (Shadowing)

2012

• Observed Dr. Slavin, pediatrics and clinical geneticist, in the Medical Genetics section, City of Hope (9 hours/month)

Certifications

IRB Training March 2019

Life Sciences Responsible Conduct of Research Course (RCR) March 2019

Medical School Pathology – Certificate of Achievement June 2018

DNA Research with Biopython Nov 2017

Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp with R Oct 2017

Google's Go (golang) Programming Language Oct 2017

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Sep 2017

Community Service

Market Research. Berkeley Humane	2014
Animal Welfare	
Community Wellness Advocate. American Cancer Society	2014
Social Services	

International Experience

Teacher. English Language	Summer 2005
• Thailand, Laos	
Violinist. Orchestra	Summer 2006
France, Belgium	

Technical Skills

Computer proficiency (MS office, Stats, SAS, R), 7 years of lab and research experience, technical writing, strong organizational and leadership skills, project management, Organizational leadership

Professional Organization Membership

The American Society for Cell Biology (ASCB)	2019
American Society for Microbiology University of Florida Student Chapter (ASM Gators)	2019
The Journal of Experimental Biology Transforming the Future through Science Federation of American Societies for Experimental Biology	2014
The Journal of Immunology (AAI)	2013

AAI Centennial

A Century of Excellence: Celebrating 100 Years of The Journal of Immunology The American Association of Immunologists, Inc.

Hobbies

Designing, Drafting, Drawing, Stagecraft, Lighting and Sound, Violin Music, Travelling, Photography, Cooking, Health and Fitness